Guide to the George Amberg and Robert Gessner Papers MC.199
New York University Archives
- Series V: Writings
  - Subseries B: Writings of Robert Gessner
    - See You Tomorrow: an original for TV, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042278021
    - "Sex Out of Focus", 1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      and related correspondence
    - "The Stranger Goes to Jail", undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Some Notes on Cinematic Movements", 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Teaching is Sharing" U.S. Air Force Instructional Methods Part I, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Television Goes to College, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Includes film programs 1957-1958
    - Treason, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Two Sides to the Equator: an original screen treatment, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      By Harold and Robert Gessner
    - Untitled Folder - "There is an African at the Gate", "Seven Faces of Time", "Teaching the Screenplay", undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Folder - "Youth at the Studio Gate", "In Search of the Third Eye", "The Power Behind Polish Films", undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "We've Eliminated Every Neurosis but Jealousy", undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Writings on Cinema, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Writings - Notebooks, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Writings - Notebook, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Writings - Poetry, Prose, Score, 1934-1935, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "The Year They Stopped the Commercials", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Films
  - About Town
    - No Slate Wanamaker's, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-1,2 (Box 20)
    - Metro Museum, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-3,4,5 (Box 20)
    - Metropolitan/Opera Ballet, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-6,7,8,9,10,11 (Box 21)
    - U.N. Building, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-12,13,14 (Box 20)
    - New U.N. Stuff, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-15,16,17,18,19,20 (Box 20)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-21,22,23,24,25,26 (Box 20)
    - U.N. + Boids + Round or Square Shot, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-27,28,29,30,31 (Box 20)
    - Untitled, from Around Town: UN, Metropolitan, Mod. Art, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-33,34,35 (Box 20)
    - People to U.N., 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-37,38,39,40,41,42,43,44 (Box 20)
    - Bldgs, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-46,47,48,49,50,51,52 (Box 21)
    - Steuben Store, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-53,54,55,56,57 (Box 21)
    - Out Pedestrians, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-59,69,61,62,63,64,65,66 (Box 21)
    - Around Grand Central (turn into darkness), 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-58 (Box 21)
    - On 47[41?] Bldg, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-67,68,69,70,71,72,73,74,75,76,77,78,79 (Box 21)
    - Day Store Window, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-80 (Box 21)
    - Pedestrians, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-81,82,83,84,85,86,87,88,89,90 (Box 21)
    - Untitled from Around Town: Polish+Sweep, Night Mat'l; subway, cars + cabs, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-91,92,93,94,95,96 (Box 21)
    - Subway Uptown, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-97,98 (Box 21)
    - Untitled from Around Town: Polish+Sweep, Night Mat'l; subway, cars +cabs, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-99,100,101,102,103,104,105 (Box 21)
    - Subway, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-106,107,108,109,110,11 (Box 22)
    - Polish + Sweep, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-112,113,114,115,116,117 (Box 22)
    - Ferry Area People Pass 5+10, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-118,119,120 (Box 22)
    - Lever House, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-121, 122,123 (Box 22)
    - Lever Bldg, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-124,125,126 (Box 22)
    - Lever House Interior, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-127,128,129,130 (Box 22)
    - Untitled from Around Town: Lever House, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-131 (Box 22)
    - Untitled from Around Town: Lever House 1, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-132 (Box 22)
    - South Ferry Area - With Milling People, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-133,134,135,136,137 (Box 22)
    - Ferry Area - Passing Pillared Bldgs, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-138,139,140,141 (Box 22)
    - Ferry - People at Bus Stop, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-142,143,144,145,146,147,148 (Box 23)
    - Ferry High Angle People, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-149,150,151,152 (Box 23)
    - Nite Store Windows, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-153,154,155,156,157,158,159,160,161,162,163,164 (Box 23)
    - Night Manhattan Bldgs, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-165,166,167 (Box 23)
    - Out Dusk To Night Dissolve, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-168 (Box 23)
    - Day To Night, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-169,170,171,172,173,174 (Box 23)
    - Nite Bldgs, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-175 (Box 23)
    - Window with Mirror Ball, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-176 (Box 23)
    - Out Bldgs at Night, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-177 (Box 23)
    - Night Pedestrians, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-178,179,180,181,182,183,184,185 (Box 23)
    - Window-Panto Street (NSG), 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-186 (Box 24)
    - Winter Garden, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-187 (Box 24)
    - Greek Theater, 1952; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; 1 film reels MC199-188,189,190 (Box 24)
    - Tavern on the Green, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-191,192,193,194 (Box 24)
    - Spaghetti Joint, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-195,196,197,198 (Box 24)
    - People Theatre Marquees, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-199,200,201,202,203,204 (Box 24)
    - Theater Audience, 1952; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Amberg, George, 1901-1971; 1 film reels MC199-205,206,207,208,209,210 (Box 24)
    - L.S. NY High Angle, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-218,219,220 (Box 24)
    - Chinatown 1, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-221 (Box 24)
    - Chinatown 2, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-222 (Box 24)
    - Posters (Beethoven), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-223,224 (Box 25)
    - LS Time Square Night, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-225 (Box 25)
    - Untitled from Around Town: March of Time, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-226 (Box 25)
    - Skyscrapers, wall st., 1952; 1 film reels MC199-227,228,229,230,231,232,233,234,235,236,237,238,239,240,241,242 (Box 25)
    - Constuction, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-243,244,245,246,247,248,249,250,251 (Box 25)
    - NY Parks (Out), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-252,253,254,255,256 (Box 25)
    - E. River Drive, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-257,258,259,260 (Box 25)
    - Uptown, Side Bridge, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-261 (Box 25)
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-262 (Box 25)
    - Skyscrapers, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-263,264,265 (Box 26)
    - Smoky out stop motion manhattan, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-266 (Box 26)
    - Cities + Bldgs Nig, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-267, 268 (Box 26)
    - Grand Central Out, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-269 (Box 26)
    - Treas. Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-270 (Box 26)
    - Out Modern Bldg, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-271 (Box 26)
    - Outtake Park Ave, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-272 (Box 26)
    - Bob Walks to School, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-273,274,275,276,277,278,279,280,281,282,283 (Box 26)
    - Opening Shop French Line, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-284,285,286,287 (Box 27)
    - Gallery, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-288, 289,290,291,292 (Box 27)
    - Empire Theater, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-293,294 (Box 27)
    - Bank, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-294,295,296 (Box 27)
    - Piano Store, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-297,298,299,300,301 (Box 27)
    - Bali Theater, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-302,303,304 (Box 27)
    - Fruit Market, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-305,306,307 (Box 27)
    - Bob Walks to School Trims, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-308,309,310,311 (Box 27)
    - Polishing sweeping fruit on stand (lift), 1952; 1 film reels MC199-312,313 (Box 28)
    - Untitled from Around Town: Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-314 (Box 28)
    - Door Lock, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-315,316,317 (Box 28)
    - Untitled from Around Town 1: Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-315,316,317 (Box 28)
    - Untitled from Around Town 2, Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-318,319,320 (Box 28)
    - Untitled from Around Town 3, Opening Stores, Bob Walks, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-321,322,323,324 (Box 28)
    - Out-Park Ave, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-325 (Box 28)
    - Stage, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-211,212,213,214 (Box 28)
    - Central Pk Boats, 1952; 1 film reels MC199-215,216,217 (Box 28)
- Series VII: Non-English Material
  - Box 14: Assorted Papers (film studio promotional material, film periodicals, typewritten memos, posters, art catalogs) (Box 14)
  - Box 15: Subject Files (film index cards with attached newspaper clippings, 1930s-1960s) (Box 15)
    This box contains an alphabetically filed collection of index cards, on which are printed newspaper clippings about feature films. The clippings provide information about the film's premise, the actors, the director, and local showing times. The films included in the box range in date from the 1930s to the 1960s.
    barcode#:31142042278047
  - Box 16: Photographs (prints from UNESCO Archives, portraits of filmmakers and film subjects) (Box 16)
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks
  - Treason, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Robert Gessner, 1945-1972 (Box 18)
  - Scrapbook compiled by Gessner on instruction at NYU, 1936-1953 (Box 19)